<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<resources>
	<string-array name="tingri">
		<item/>
		<item> If you spend the present meaninglessly and leave with empty hands, People of Tingri, a human life in the future will be very hard to find.  </item>
		<item> To apply yourselves with body, speech and mind to the sacred Teachings, People of Tingri, is the best thing that you can do.  </item>
		<item> Give your very life, heart and soul to the Three Jewels [the Buddha, the Dharma, and the Sangha], People of Tingri, and their blessings cannot but arise.  </item>
		<item> Forget your goals for this life - concentrate instead on lives to come. People of Tingri, that is the highest goal.  </item>
		<item> Families are as fleeting as a crowd on market day; People of Tingri, don\'t bicker or fight.  </item>
		<item> Wealth and poverty, like a magic show, just seduce and deceive; People of Tingri, don\'t let the knot of avarice bind you.  </item>
		<item> This body\'s just a bag containing various kinds of filth; People of Tingri, don\'t pamper it and spruce it up so.  </item>
		<item> Family and friends are no more real than a magic show; People of Tingri, in your fondness for them don\'t tie yourself down.  </item>
		<item> Country and land are like a nomad\'s pastures People of Tingri, don\'t cling sentimentally to them.  </item>
		<item> As parents, all beings in the six realms have cared for you; People of Tingri, don\'t relate to them with your ideas of "I" and "mine".  </item>
		<item> The day you were born,  your death began approaching; People of Tingri, remember: there is never any time to spare.  </item>
		<item> Fundamentally there\'s no delusion, it\'s an ephemeral occurrence; People of Tingri, look at the nature of what it produces.  </item>
		<item> Without distraction apply yourselves to the sacred Dharma; People of Tingri, after death it will guide you on the path.  </item>
		<item> The truth of cause and effect ensures that actions yield their full result; People of Tingri, avoid all actions that are negative and evil.  </item>
		<item> Leave all your activities behind like a country in a dream; People of Tingri, just put non-action into practice.  </item>
		<item> The very thing you feel attached to, let go of it, whatever - People of Tingri, there isn\'t anything that you need.  </item>
		<item> Since you won\'t be staying in this world forever, People of Tingri, make your preparations for the journey now.  </item>
		<item> If you first finish what you have to do,  you\'ll never get to Dharma; People of Tingri, while you\'re thinking about it, practice straight away.  </item>
		<item> Inside the forest, monkeys may be living happily at ease, People of Tingri - but at the edges forest fires are closing in all round.  </item>
		<item> Birth, sickness, ageing and death flow on, a river without ford or bridge; People of Tingri, have you prepared yourselves a boat?  </item>
		<item> In the narrow defiles of birth, death and the intermediate state Bandits await - the five poisonous emotions - sure to ambush you; People of Tingri, avail yourselves of the teacher as your escort.  </item>
		<item> Your never-failing source of refuge is the teacher; People of Tingri, carry him constantly on the crown of your head.  </item>
		<item> If your protection is the teacher, you\'ll reach wherever you aspire to go; People of Tingri, cultivate devotion as the fare you pay for the journey.  </item>
		<item> Those who get wealthy get miserly too; People of Tingri, give generously without being partial.  </item>
		<item> Whoever gets power acts sinfully, too; People of Tingri, abandon all desire for rank and power.  </item>
		<item> Those with rank and riches are never happy and at ease; People of Tingri, get ready to claw at your chest in anguish.  </item>
		<item> In the next world, there are neither family nor friends; People of Tingri, place your confidence in the Dharma.  </item>
		<item> If you wander in distraction, you\'ll waste the freedoms and advantages of human life; People of Tingri,  make a resolute decision now.  </item>
		<item> While you\'re busy being distracted, the demon of Death will catch you; People of Tingri, practice from this very moment onwards.  </item>
		<item> When will the demon of Death appear? There is no easy way to tell; People of Tingri, right now be always on your guard.  </item>
		<item> The day you die, there\'s no one who\'ll protect you; People of Tingri, be ready to have yourselves alone to count on.  </item>
		<item> If you reflect on death, there\'s nothing you will need; People of Tingri, always keep your death in mind.  </item>
		<item> Like lengthening shadows as the sun sinks low, The demon of Death relentlessly draws nearer; People of Tingri, quickly! Get away from him!  </item>
		<item> The morning\'s ravishing flower will wither by nightfall; People of Tingri, don\'t put your hopes in your body.  </item>
		<item> Even if resembling, while alive, the children of the gods, Once dead they are more frightful than a demon horde; People of Tingri, you\'ve been deceived by these illusory bodies.  </item>
		<item> Visitors to market day, their trading finished, on the morrow have dispersed; People of Tingri, your friends will part from you, be certain.  </item>
		<item> Since the scarecrow conjured up by magic is sure to tumble down; People of Tingri, act now according to the linking of effect with cause.  </item>
		<item> For sure, the vulture of your mind will one day fly away; People of Tingri, now is the time to soar up to the heights.  </item>
		<item> All beings of the six realms have cared for you as parents; People of Tingri, towards them cultivate your love and compassion.  </item>
		<item> Hate for enemies is samsara\'s hallucination, caused by actions; People of Tingri, transmute your hatred and your hostile mind.  </item>
		<item> Prostration and circumambulation purify obscuration of the body; People of Tingri, abandon all your worldly physical work.  </item>
		<item> Recitation and taking refuge purify obscuration of the speech; People of Tingri, abandon all your ordinary conversation.  </item>
		<item> Fervent devotion purifies habitual tendencies of the mind; People of Tingri, meditate on the teacher above your head.  </item>
		<item> Your flesh and bones took form together, but in the end are sure to separate; People of Tingri, do not believe that you will live forever.  </item>
		<item> Capture that most sublime of countries, the constant land of the natural state; People of Tingri, where there is no transition or change.  </item>
		<item> Enjoy that most sublime of riches, the treasure of the nature of mind; People of Tingri, which cannot ever be depleted.  </item>
		<item> Savor that most sublime of foods, the exquisite taste of meditation, People of Tingri, which abolishes the pangs of hunger.  </item>
		<item> Imbibe that most sublime of drinks, the ambrosia of mindfulness, People of Tingri, whose flow is never interrupted.  </item>
		<item> Rely upon that most sublime companion, primordial awareness wisdom, People of Tingri, from which you never can be parted.  </item>
		<item> Seek for that most sublime of progeny, the young child pure awareness, People of Tingri, for which there is no birth or death.  </item>
		<item> In a state of emptiness, whirl the spear of pure awareness; People of Tingri, the view is free of being caught by anything at all.  </item>
		<item> In a state without thoughts, without distraction, abandon the watcher; People of Tingri, the meditation is free of any torpor or excitement.  </item>
		<item> In a state of natural spontaneity, train in being free of any holding back; People of Tingri, in the action there is nothing to abandon or adopt.  </item>
		<item> The four bodies, indivisible, are complete in your mind; People of Tingri, the fruit is beyond all hope and doubt.  </item>
		<item> The root of both samsara and nirvana is to be found within your mind; People of Tingri, the mind is free of any true reality.  </item>
		<item> Desire and hate appear, but like birds in flight, should leave no trace behind; People of Tingri, in meditation be free of clinging to experiences.  </item>
		<item> The unborn absolute body is like the very heart of the sun - People of Tingri, there is no waxing or waning of its radiant clarity.  </item>
		<item> Thoughts come and go like a thief in an empty house - People of Tingri, in fact there is nothing to be gained or lost.  </item>
		<item> Sensations leave no imprints, like drawings made on water; People of Tingri, don\'t perpetuate deluded appearances.  </item>
		<item> Thoughts of attachment and aversion are like rainbows in the sky; People of Tingri, there is nothing in them to be grasped or apprehended.  </item>
		<item> Mind\'s movements dissolve by themselves, like clouds in the sky; People of Tingri, in the mind there are no reference points.  </item>
		<item> Without fixation, thoughts are freed by themselves, like the wind, People of Tingri, which never clings to any object.  </item>
		<item> Pure awareness is without fixation, like a rainbow in the sky; People of Tingri, experiences arise quite unimpededly.  </item>
		<item> Realization of the absolute nature is like the dream of a mute; People of Tingri, there are no words to express it.  </item>
		<item> Realization is like a youthful maiden\'s pleasure; People of Tingri, the joy and bliss cannot be described.  </item>
		<item> Clarity and emptiness united are like the moon reflecting in water; People of Tingri, there is nothing to be attached to and nothing to impede.  </item>
		<item> Appearances and emptiness inseparable are like the empty sky; People of Tingri, the mind is without either center or periphery.  </item>
		<item> The mind with no thought and no distraction is like the mirror of a beauty; People of Tingri, it is free of any theoretical tenets.  </item>
		<item> Awareness and emptiness inseparable are like reflections in a mirror; People of Tingri, nothing is born there and nothing ceases.  </item>
		<item> Bliss and emptiness inseparable are like the sun lighting up the snows; People of Tingri, there is nothing there to apprehend.  </item>
		<item> Deluded talk will fade without a trace, like echoes; People of Tingri, in sound there is nothing to be grasped.  </item>
		<item> Happiness and suffering, through a mechanism like the sounding of a lute\'s body and strings, People of Tingri, are produced when actions are combined with necessary conditions.  </item>
		<item> The natural freedom of samsara and nirvana is like a children\'s game; People of Tingri, have a mind without any aims.  </item>
		<item> Your notions of the outer world derive from the mind within; People of Tingri, let the solid ice be melted into liquid.  </item>
		<item> The mechanism of ignorance is like the gush of a meadow spring; People of Tingri, it cannot be halted by obstructing it.  </item>
		<item> The delusions of samsara and nirvana are like coming face to face with an enemy; People of Tingri, as your ally practice virtue.  </item>
		<item> The natural clarity of the five kayas [aspects of enlightenment] is like the expanse of a continent of gold; People of Tingri, there is no hope or doubt, attachment or aversion.  </item>
		<item> With its freedoms and advantages, human life is like a treasure island; People of Tingri, do not come back an empty-handed failure.  </item>
		<item> The practice of the Great Vehicle is like a wish-fulfilling gem; People of Tingri, however hard you search, it would be difficult to find again.  </item>
		<item> For this life, come what may, you\'ll have enough to eat and clothe yourself; People of Tingri, put everything you have into practicing the Dharma.  </item>
		<item> While you are young, practice hard and with austerities; People of Tingri, once you\'re old your constitution won\'t withstand it.  </item>
		<item> When emotions arise, bring antidotes to bear on them; People of Tingri, let free all concepts in their very nature.  </item>
		<item> Think from time to time of all the defects of samsara; People of Tingri, that will make your faith become much clearer.  </item>
		<item> Right now, develop diligence and stand your ground; People of Tingri, when you die it will guide you on the path.  </item>
		<item> If you\'re not free now, when will you ever get to be free? People of Tingri, your chance to eat comes only one time in a hundred.  </item>
		<item> Life is so ephemeral, like the dew on the grass; People of Tingri, don\'t yield to laziness and indifference.  </item>
		<item> From where you are now, should you lose your footing, People of Tingri, it will be hard to find a human life again.  </item>
		<item> The Buddha\'s teaching is like the sun shining through the clouds; People of Tingri, now is the one time that it is present.  </item>
		<item> You say such clever things to people, but don\'t apply them to yourself; People of Tingri, the faults within you are the ones to be exposed.  </item>
		<item> That faith succumbs to circumstance is only a short step away; People of Tingri, contemplate samsara\'s imperfections.  </item>
		<item> Frequenting evil friends is bound to make your own behavior evil; People of Tingri, abandon any friendships that are negative.  </item>
		<item> Frequenting virtuous friends is bound to make your own good qualities arise; People of Tingri, follow your spiritual teachers.  </item>
		<item> Deception and lies deceive not only others, but yourself as well; People of Tingri, as witness take your own conscience.  </item>
		<item> Delusion born from ignorance is the worst disaster-bearing demon; People of Tingri, hold fast to your vigilance and mindfulness.  </item>
		<item> If you don\'t hold on to the three or five poisons [desire, hatred, ignorance, jealousy, pride], the path is near; People of Tingri, generate powerful antidotes against them.  </item>
		<item> If your perseverance has no strength, you will not reach Buddhahood; People of Tingri, make sure that you don that Armor.  </item>
		<item> Habitual tendencies, being old acquaintances, keep on coming back; People of Tingri, don\'t go on following the past.  </item>
		<item> If your understanding and realization are weak, pray to your lord teacher; People of Tingri, and deep meditation will be born in you.  </item>
		<item> If you aspire to happiness in future, accept your present trials; People of Tingri - then Buddhahood is right here just beside you.  </item>
		<item> This old Indian master will not stay in Tingri, he will go away; People of Tingri, it is now that you must clarify your doubts.  </item>
	</string-array>
</resources>
